*BGM~*
一群朋友正在玩 《D&D》
注：龙与地下城 Dungeons and Dragons
A group of friends is partway through a game of D&D.
他们靠在一起 听他们的地下城城主（DM）发话
They lean in together and listen to their dungeon master.
好的 你拿起法杖念着咒语
Okay, so you're casting the, so yeah, you grab your staff
把自然的力量注入其中
and you channel the forces of nature into it.
你可以看到藤蔓从里面伸出来 和你结合在一起
And you can see vines coming out of it and it just bonds to you.
它在你手中的重量明显不同了 你感觉到了更强大的力量
And you, it feels differently weighted in your hands now and you feel much more powerful.
你本回合已经施了这个魔法…
So that's what you do, you cast a spell this round...
好的你做到了 你还有一次行动机会
Alright, so you do that and you still have an action.
你要做什么呢？
What do you do?
*BGM*
好吧 我得承认：
Okay, a confession:
我小的时候 从来没有坐在地下室里玩过《D&D》游戏
when I was growing up I never sat in a basement playing D&D.
我也从没有渴望过成为一名 DM 不管它是什么
I did not long to be a dungeon master, whatever that is.
我不会在真人角色扮演游戏中的树林里找我的第一个男朋友
I did not find my first boyfriend while LARPing in the woods
*真可悲~*
Pathetic~
也不会在漫展的过道上和我的死党黏在一起
or bond with my BFF while cruising the aisles at Comic-Con.
那不是我
It just wasn't me.
*苍白地反驳*
但我知道的是 游戏把人们聚集到了一起并形成了社区
But what I do get is that games brought people together into communities.
而且 对于众多的开发者而言 游戏是编程的入门良方
And, for a huge number of developers out there, games were the gateway drug into programming.
正是游戏让他们了解计算机
It was games that taught them about computers
并第一次将他们带入一个以极客为骄傲的空间
and got them in a room where they could geek out with pride for the first time.
正是对游戏的热爱让他们想自己开发一款游戏
It was the love of gameplay that made them want to build a game themselves.
然后他们超越了游戏的范畴 进入更为广大的软件开发领域
Then go beyond gameplay to just build.
这是我非常喜欢的东西
And that's something I'm very much into.
在第一季中 我们探讨了开源从何而来
In our first season, we explored where open source came from,
以及它是如何影响了开发者世界中的每一个环节
and how it's shaping every part of the developer's world.
这一季我们就在代码里面讲述：
This season we're living right on the command line itself:
如今 成为一名开发人员究竟意味着什么？
what it means to be a developer today.
这一切都是从找到你的伙伴开始的
And all that starts with finding your people.
那么来吧 游戏开始了！
So let the games begin.
*BGM*
甚至在“开源”和“互联网”这两个术语被创造之前
Before the terms open source and internet were even coined,
就已经有了游戏玩家
there were gamers
那些游戏玩家想要相互连接起来
And those gamers wanted to connect with each other.
当世界开始联网时 他们走在了前列
When the world started going online, they were at the front of the pack.
他们要建立连接和共享所需的一切 并且
And they would build whatever it took to connect and share and—
哦 它上楼了
Oh, and it goes up.
哦天哪 它发怒了
Oh nice. And it goes crazy.
现在这把武器的伤害骰是 8
Yep, the weapon's damage die becomes 8.
随便你 来吧！
There you go, you were right.
所以 捅它！耶！
So stab it, yeah.
捅谁 德鲁伊吗？
Which, the druid--
我干掉它了！
I did it!
好吧 接着玩吧
Yeah, and play.
*BGM~*
我是 Saron Yitbarek
I'm Saron Yitbarek
这里是红帽原创播客《代码英雄》第二季
and this is season two of Command Line Heroes,
今天的节目是《按下启动键 游戏和开源社区》
Today's episode, Press Start, gaming and open source communities.
你站在一条路的尽头 前面是一座砖砌的小型建筑
You are standing at the end of a road before a small, brick building.
你周围是一片森林
Around you is a forest.
一条小溪从建筑物里流出 顺着沟壑而下
A small stream flows out of the building and down a gully.
你对这些话有印象吗？
Do you recognize those words?
如果你还记得 可以给你的历史知识打 10 分
If you do, ten points for knowing your history.
如果你和我一样 对它们没有印象
But, if you're like me and they did not ring a bell,
那么这些都是 《巨洞探险》的开场白
those are the opening lines of Colossal Cave Adventure.
什么是《巨洞探险》？
What is Colossal Cave Adventure?
我的朋友 一切的改变始于 1976 年
That, my friend, is the 1976 game that changed everything.
那条路 森林边的砖房
That road, that brick building by the forest,
那条流入沟壑的小溪 当时没有人知道
that stream flowing down into a gully, nobody knew it at the time,
但这款基于文本的游戏（是的 根本没有图形）
but this text-based game—yep, no graphics at all—
将是一扇闪亮的红色大门 通向了新的社区和协作形式
would be a shiny red door that led the way to new forms of community and collaboration.
*放映机播放声*
《巨洞探险》是一种被称为文字冒险的游戏
Colossal Cave Adventure was a type of game that's known as a text-based adventure.
你可以通过输入命令与计算机交互：
You interact with the computer by typing in commands:
向西走、拿上剑、爬山等等
go west, get sword, climb mountain.
这是 Jon-Paul Dyson
That's Jon-Paul Dyson.
他是 斯特朗国家游乐博物馆的副馆长
He's a VP at the Strong National Museum of Play
也是其电子游戏历史中心的主任
and the director of their Center for the History of Electronic Games.
是的 相当有趣的工作
So, yeah, pretty fun job.
《巨洞探险》是一种非常不同类型的游戏
Colossal Cave Adventure was a very different type of game.
它更像是一款流程自由的探险游戏
It was more of a free flowing, exploratory game,
就像在此时问世的《龙与地下城》一样
like Dungeons and Dragons, which comes out at just this moment in time.
因此 它开启了想象力
And so it opens the imagination.
这是一款真正革命性的游戏…
So it was a really revolutionary game...
在 70 年代中期出现了一种新型游戏 这绝非偶然
It's no accident that a new kind of game appeared in the mid-'70s.
正在其时 互联网的前身 - 阿帕网（ARPANET）出现了
Right at that time, the internet's granddaddy, the ARPANET, was coming to life.
事情是这样的 一位在 ARPANET 上工作的人
What happened is, one of the guys working on ARPANET,
他叫 Will Crowther
a guy named Will Crowther,
有了开发这个洞穴探险游戏的想法
had this idea for developing this cave exploration game.
他大致依据他曾探索过的 肯塔基州猛犸象洞穴的一部分为基础
Now he created this game based loosely on a section of Mammoth Cave in Kentucky
创作了这款游戏
that he had explored.
这真是革命性的突破 因为它给了玩家一个探索环境的机会
And it was really revolutionary in the way that it gave players a chance to explore this environment.
不过更有趣的是 他去度假了
But what's interesting was because ARPANET was now around,
而另一个人 叫 Don Woods 的伙计
and someone else, this guy, Don Woods,
因为当时 ARPANET 的存在而发现了这个游戏
was able to discover the game,
然后做了些调整
and then make all these adjustments.
因此几乎从一开始 这个游戏的开发就是一个协作过程
So almost from the very beginning, the game was a collaborative process
因为它已在网络上被共享
because it had been shared on this network.
这恰是一个很好的例子
And it was just a good example of
说明了游戏是如何被开发、修改、改进 然后广泛传播的
how a game could be developed, and modified, improved and then distributed widely
这一切都是因为这些计算机是连接在一起的
because these computers were connected.
因此 在计算机联网后
So immediately after computers become networked,
我们可以立即开始使用这些网络来分享游戏
we're starting to use those networks to share games.
而这些游戏本身也在不断演变
And those games are evolving along the way.
事情是这样的：
Here's the thing, though:
不仅仅是网络改善了游戏
it wasn't just networks improving games,
游戏也改善了网络
it was also games improving networks.
因为越多的人想要分享这些游戏
Because the more people wanted to share those games,
他们就越需要社区的论坛
the more they needed usable forums for a community.
因此 有了游戏技术 以及热爱它们的社区 它们彼此在相互促进
So you've got game technology and the communities that love them sort of egging each other on.
这是一个正反馈回路
A positive feedback loop.
*诡异~*
同样 游戏开发人员彼此启发 相互借鉴
Likewise, the game developers are inspired by each other, growing off each other's ideas.
ARPANET 真是一片肥沃的土地
The ARPANET was hugely fertile ground.
Jon-Paul Dyson 再次发言：
Here's Jon-Paul Dyson again:
所以像《冒险》这样的文字冒险游戏就在这种环境里流转
So text-based adventures like Adventure operated at this space that
这一环境被技术先锋们占据
that was occupied by pioneering technologists
他们知道如何无厘头、搞笑 知道如何才好玩
who also knew how to be silly, laugh, and to have fun.
早期的游戏确实为开发者社区该如何协同工作提供了一种模式
Early games really offer a pattern for how communities of developers can work together.
请记住 我们这里并不是在讨论 Minecraft
Remember, we're not talking about Minecraft here,
也不是《英雄联盟》
we're not talking about League of Legends,
我们谈论的是黑色屏幕上一行行绿色的文字
we're talking about lines of green text on a black screen
读完游戏内置的故事
just reading out a story-based game
并让你做出决定
and inviting you to make your decisions.
这是一种相当简单的游戏文化
It's a much simpler gaming culture.
但它给了我们巨大的回报
But it gave us huge rewards.
有一种共同体的信念 认为分享有好处
There's this communitarian belief in the benefits of sharing,
即与生产专有产品相比 更多的协作可以产生更好的结果
that more collaboration produces better results than producing proprietary products.
结果就是你开发的游戏都是从社区中涌现出来的
And so the result is that you have games developed that emerged out of communities
这些游戏本身对改变持开放态度
and that are themselves open to being changed
并鼓励人们改变游戏
and encouraging people to make changes
可能是小的方面 也可能是大的方面
that might alter the game in minor ways or significant ways.
但有一种感觉是 如果游戏变得更好 那么一切都是好的
But there's a feeling that if the game is made better, then that's all for the good.
所以我认为历史上的这种早期的理念
And so I think there's this early spirit in the history,
尤其是计算机游戏方面 在推动计算机社区的发展方面确实很重要
especially of computer games, that really is important in pushing forth computer communities
Dennis Jerz 教授特别研究了游戏的历史
Professor Dennis Jerz has studied the history of games
尤其是《巨洞探险》
and Colossal Cave Adventure in particular.
对他来说
For him,
这些原始开源社区对于所有创造力来说
these proto-open-source communities
都是一次自由的释放
were a free for all of creativity.
当时的文化是
The culture at the time
人们在自己工作的基础上建立和分享自己的想法
involved people building upon and sharing their own ideas.
而且很常见的是找到源代码后
And it was very common to find the source code,
第一件事就是
and then the first thing you would do is
在现有的源代码上再增加一个属于自己的空间
add another room to the existing source code.
这和同人创作的想法很像
It was pretty much like the idea of fan fiction,
就是人们创造自己的故事
the whole idea that you have people who are creating their own stories
这些故事穿插在《哈利·波特》的不同章节之间
that fit in between various chapters of Harry Potter books
或者是《饥饿游戏》中 Katniss 的世界里的小角色的故事
or here's what happened to the minor characters in Katniss' world from the Hunger Games.
这种在主叙事的基础上进行补充、阐述和构建的文化
This culture of adding to, and elaborating and building upon a main narrative.
好吧 所以我现在急着要找 Van Tyler
Okay, so I am rushing over now to Van Tyler
看看她的伤口
and looking at her wounds.
哦 上面说武器的伤害变成了 d8
Oh, the weapon's damage becomes a d8, it says.
注：d8 指“骰一次 8 面骰子所得数值”
在基于图像或视频的游戏出现之前
Before image or video-based gaming,
这些基于想象力的游戏风格为大规模的在线社区铺平了道路
these imagination-based game styles paved the way for massive online communities down the road.
游戏社区和在线社区之间的是共生的 拥有强韧的联系
The relationship between gaming and online communities was symbiotic and powerful.
但如果说有一件事是游戏玩家都知道
But if there's one thing the gaming crowd knows,
那就是强大的玩家可以将任务推动到一个新的方向
it's that powerful players can swerve the mission in a new direction.
随着网络游戏的发展 它以社区为基础的根基开始被侵蚀
As online gaming grew up, its community-based roots have started to erode.
这次试着把它放在他的脖子后面
And this time try to bring it down on the back of his neck.
搞定！
Yeah!
好的 让我们快进到如今
Okay, let's fast forward to today.
互联网已经成熟
The internet's all grown up.
有了它 在线游戏社区已经有了很大进步
And with it, the online gaming community has leveled-up. A lot.
注：level-up 在游戏中一般指升级
如今 游戏每年的收入超过 1000 亿美元
Gaming today generates more than 100 billion in revenue each year.
预计在未来的十年 这个数字还将再翻一倍
And that's expected to more than double in the next decade.
*硬币声*
但这样的成功也改变了游戏规则
But all that success has also changed the game.
这不是一群独立开发者
It's not a group of indie developers
在一个摇摇欲坠的论坛上分享他们的作品
sharing their work on a rickety forum.
如今的游戏社区与《巨洞探险》时期的情况完全不同
Game communities that exist today are radically different
from what was going on in the early days of Colossal Cave Adventure.
大家好 我叫 Saku
Hi, my name is Saku,
我是一家名为 Asteroid 的初创公司的创始人
I'm the founder of a startup called Asteroid,
我公司为游戏开发者制作增强现实（AR）工具
which makes augmented reality tools for game developers.
Saku Panditharatne 觉得开放的互联网与游戏开发之间的关系
Saku Panditharatne wonders if that relationship between the open internet and game development
最近已经扭曲
has gotten a bit twisted lately.
她说的很清楚 为什么游戏公司之间不共享部分代码
She's got a point, why aren't parts of code shared between game companies
而有时候大型科技公司之间却能共享代码呢？
the same way code is sometimes shared between big tech companies?
如果你是唯一一个与所有人共享你的代码的游戏公司
If you’re the only game company that shares your code with everyone,
那么你的竞争对手只会复制你的代码
your competitors will just copy you,
他们会拿走你的所有秘密
and they'll take all your secrets
并且他们会制作出比你更好的 3A 游戏
and they'll make a better triple-A game than you.
这对大型科技公司来说也是个问题
And that was also a problem for big tech companies as well.
但实际上 我认为是软件工程师的努力打破了这种平衡
But it was the efforts of software engineers that actually, I think, broke this equilibrium
因为如果没有人为一家闭源的公司工作
Because if no one worked for a company that kept its code source,
那么每个人都会被迫开源
then everyone was forced to go open source
然后所有的大科技公司都会尽可能地共享
and then you get all the big tech companies sharing as much as they can,
这对软件整体来说是非常好的
which is very good for software as a whole.
但这在游戏行业中从未发生过
But that never happened with games.
Saku 的理论是 与其他领域相比
Saku's theory that traditionally in gaming
在游戏领域的传统上 开发者没有同样的决策控制权
the developers haven't had the same control over decision making compared to other fields.
那太糟糕了 因为这意味着我们都错过了开放
And that's too bad, because it means we're all missing out.
我们基本上知道具体如何
We basically know exactly how to
将渲染、着色以及物理模拟做到很高的标准
do rendering and shading and physics to a really high standard.
那不应该是每个游戏工作室都在重新发明的东西
And that shouldn't be something that every single game studio is replicating.
但是奇怪的是 游戏工作室通常仍会在内部构建引擎
But, weirdly enough, it is often the case that games studios still will build engines in-house.
不幸的是 他们陷入了这种…
Unfortunately, they're stuck in this kind of ...
我觉得游戏有点像电影 而不是像软件
I kind of feel like games are a bit more like film than they are like software.
游戏可能会陷入开发地狱
You get games stuck in development hell.
你会遇到各种问题 比如制作人的融资问题等等
You get all these problems with producers financing them and stuff like that.
我认为所有这些因素都不利于软件变得更好
And I think all these factors work against adopting the best possible software.
*BGM*
因此 游戏开发中的专有制度
So, that proprietary approach in game development
导致了大量重复的工作
leads to a lot of redundant work.
每个工作室都必须解决同样的问题
Every studio is forced to solve the same problems.
而且它们中的大多数都不是最佳解决方案
And most of them aren't optimal solutions, either.
同时 对于可能会提供新东西的独立开发人员来说
Meantime, things quickly become unaffordable for indie developers
事情很快变得难以承受
that might have something new to offer.
游戏开发人员通常必须购买某个主流游戏引擎的许可证
Game developers often have to buy licenses for one of the major game engines.
或者 他们必须得购买灯光脚本之类的工具
Or, they'll have to buy, say, a lighting script.
另一方面 Web 开发人员拥有更多可接受的选择
Web developers, on the other hand, have way more affordable options.
我觉得真正有趣的一个事实是
One fact I find really interesting is that
拍一部电影比做一架飞机更复杂
it's more complex to make a movie than it is to make an airplane.
这是因为你需要召集这样一群人 他们的技能各不相同
That's just because you have all these different people with very different skill sets,
他们的工作时间表不同
they work on a different schedule,
他们受到的激励也不同
they're incentivized by different things.
所以 让他们一起工作就像一场组织挑战
So, then, getting them to work together is like an organizational challenge.
而游戏引擎和其他游戏开发工具的作用之一就是
And one of the things that game engines and other game software does—
弥合这样的鸿沟
it's about bridging that divide
这让它们几乎成为最高效的工作软件
almost as much as it is about being the most efficient software for the job.
游戏开发的问题很像电影制作问题
Game development's problem is a lot like that movie production problem.
你有艺术家、编剧、角色设计师
You've got artists, storytellers, character designers,
都在与程序员和系统管理员角力
all wrestling with programmers and sysadmins.
如果不采取开源的态度 或者没有建立共享和同步的方式
Without adopting open source attitudes, without building in ways to share and sync up,
那一群不同角色的人就会变得混乱
that crowd of different people with different roles can get chaotic.
这一切都归结为建设社区的挑战
It all boils down to the challenge of building community.
那些最初的游戏 是由开发者利用自己的空闲
Those first games, they were being built by the developers themselves,
例如午休时间开发的
like, during their lunch breaks.
另一方面 像《魔兽世界》这样的游戏
Games like World of Warcraft, on the other hand,
他们有大量的创意人员和程序员
they've got this mammoth mix of creatives and programmers.
社区已经达到了极限
The communities get stretched to their limit.
例如 我认为没有哪个论坛
I don't think there's any forum
可以让开发人员向角色设计师提出“PR”以供审查
where developers make pull requests for character designers to review.
注：这里的 PR 即 pull request，是 git 中向储存库提交更改的方式之一
但也许应该有 “PR”
But maybe there should be.
Saku 知道我在说什么
Saku knows what I'm talking about.
我认为游戏的一个大问题是
I think one big issue for games is that
它是一个跨学科的东西
it's a cross-disciplinary thing.
跨学科做任何事情都是困难的
And doing anything cross disciplinary is difficult
因为这几乎就像 C.P.Snow Essay 的文章 《两种文化》
‘cause it was almost like the C.P.Snow essay "The Two Cultures",
你必须把用右脑的、富有创造性思维的人
you have to bring together people who are right-brained and creative-minded
用左脑的 擅长逻辑思维的人聚集在一起
and people who are left-brained and logical and get them to work together on something.
我们能不能花点时间 拜托在座的各位做一件事？
Can we just take a second to ask the world to build something?
如果 GitHub 上有人想找出一种开源游戏开发的方法
If anybody on GitHub wants to figure out a way to do open source game development
在开发者和艺术家之间进行转译
that translates for developers and artists at the same time,
你就为世界做出了贡献
you'd be doing the world a solid.
我有点觉得 游戏的限制
I kinda think that the limit to games
一直都是把两群不怎么互相对话的人聚集在一起
has always been bringing together two groups of people who don't really talk to each other
然后努力创造一些东西
and then trying to build something.
对我来说 这句话简直是在说开源的故事本身
To me, that's the story of open source in a nutshell.
特别值得一提的是 Saku 在想办法弥合两个社区之间的差距
In particular, though, Saku's imagining something to bridge the gap between two communities
从而形成一个更大的社区
to make a larger community.
是的 我认为这实际上可以真正改善整个行业
Yeah, I think it could actually really improve the industry as a whole.
我认为那些大型的新兴创业公司很多都出现在 2007 年左右
I think those big boom startups around 2007,
都是因为他们可以使用大量的开源软件
and a lot of that was because there a ton of open-source stuff you could use.
就像是 Ruby on Rails 之类的软件
Ruby on Rails you could use.
而且我认为 如果没有开发者把他们的东西免费放到网上
And I don't think that startup boom could've happened
那股创业热潮就不会发生
without developers being able to put their stuff online for free.
如果类似的事情发生在游戏行业中
If something like that happened in games,
我想我们会有比现在更多的独立游戏开发者
I think we'd have way more indie game developers than there are currently.
但有个好消息
But there's good news.
游戏领域的开源革命 可能已经开始了
That open source revolution in gaming, it might already be happening.
Jon-Paul Dyson 又言道：
Here's Jon-Paul Dyson again:
在电子游戏的历史上 确实存在两个流派：
So in the history of video games, there's really been two streams:
一个是人们创造专有产品的地方 即封闭系统
one is where people create proprietary products, their closed-end systems.
它们通常经过精心打磨 出于商业目的而发布
They're often highly polished, they release for commercial purposes.
想想像任天堂这样的公司
Think of a company like Nintendo.
任天堂创造了令人赞叹的游戏 但你无法真正进行修改
Nintendo creates amazing games and you can't really modify.
但在电子游戏和电脑游戏的历史上也出现了一种相反的趋势
But there's also been a countervailing trend in the history of video games, computer games,
这是一种更具协作性的方法
and that's been a more collaborative approach.
像《我的世界》这样的游戏
And something like Minecraft is an example of this,
就是一个现代的例子 人们正在参与对游戏的修改
a modern example, where people are making modifications to the game,
那里有一个围绕游戏而生的社区
there's a community that revolves around the game.
你可以从互联网上的某个地方下载 MOD
You download from the internet, somewhere, and this set of mods
然后在游戏中引入
that you're introducing into the game.
你拥有的是一种非常不同的
And so what you have is a very different,
几乎是有机的开发游戏的方式
almost more organic way of developing games,
而不是一种更结构化的 可能是商业化的、工程化的方式
as opposed to a more structured, maybe commercial, engineered approach.
在很多方面 《我的世界》都是诸如
Minecraft is in many ways the heir to earlier games like
《太空大战》或《巨洞探险》等早期游戏的继承者
Space War or Colossal Cave Adventure
注：《太空大战》（Space Wars）由一名大学生开发，意在复刻 PDP-1 上的游戏 spacewars!
该游戏于 1977 年，由 Cinematronics 在街机平台上发行。
该游戏在社区中发展 对进行修改和改变的人们更开放
that develops in a community and is much more open to people making modifications and changes.
注：《太空大战》（Space Wars）由一名大学生开发，意在复刻 PDP-1 上的游戏 spacewars!
该游戏于 1977 年，由 Cinematronics 在街机平台上发行。
该游戏在社区中发展 对进行修改和改变的人们更开放
that develops in a community and is much more open to people making modifications and changes.
而且 其指导思想是 从某种意义上说
And the governing philosophy is that
以长远角度来看 大众努力的成果
somehow the work of the crowd is going to be better in the long term,
将会比一个小团队或个人的作品更好
than the work of one small selected team or individual.
我认为我们现在要说的是
I think what we're getting at here is that
游戏行业并没有完成社区的建设
gaming isn't finished building communities,
你也永远不能消灭这种开源精神
you're never going to stamp out that open source spirit.
这就是我们所知道的：
Here's what we know:
游戏仍然激发了许多开发人员
gaming still inspires legions of developers.
这就是许多代码英雄最初进入该行业的原因
It's what got a lot of Command Line Heroes into this industry in the first place.
比如像 Josh Berkis 这样的代码英雄
Command Line Heroes like Josh Berkis.
嗯 我是从 Atari 800 开始的
Well, I started out on the Atari 800,
因为你可以用它设计自己的游戏
because you could design your own video games.
以及 Ann Barcomb
And Ann Barcomb.
我写的大多是冒险游戏
I wrote choose your own adventure games mostly.
那里面全是屎山代码
And it was horrible spaghetti code.
还有 Justin Flory
And Justin Flory.
在我意识到我在做开源之前 我就已经开源了
I started doing open source before I realized I was doing open source.
我从一台运行着《我的世界》的游戏服务器开始的 那时我 15 岁
I began with a game server... I was running a Minecraft server and at the time I was 15.
当人们热爱某事时
When there's this much love for something,
那么对社区、对开源的态度就会蓬勃发展
this much community, open source attitudes are going to thrive.
Saku 对于游戏开发中专有要素的警告
Saku's warnings about proprietary gaming elements
实际上正是游戏在其旅程中必须克服的障碍
are really just the hurdle that gaming has to overcome on its journey.
一些游戏行业的领先者正开始实现这一飞跃
A few leaders in gaming are starting to make that leap.
*BGM*
我们实际上做得很好
We actually did good.
我当时正在疯狂射击 我干掉了 3 个
I was on freaking fire, I had 3 kills
他们干掉了 1 个
and they had one.
哦 Campbell 带我起飞
Yeah, Campbell was carrying me.
如果你去年就快到 12 岁了
If you've been anywhere near a 12-year-old this past year,
你很可能听说过一个叫《堡垒之夜》的小游戏
you've likely heard of a little game called Fortnite.
嗯 很小的游戏
Well, little.
在它发布的第一年 它就获得了超过 1.25 亿的玩家
In its first year, it gained more than 125 million players
所有玩家都在一场大逃杀
all interacting in a massive battle royale.
我得下线了 好吧就一会 我得给我父母打个电话
I've got to, alright, one sec, I've just got to call my parents.
是的 游戏在建立社区方面还是很不错的
So, yeah, games are still pretty good at building community.
实际上 《堡垒之夜》 是有史以来最大的免费主机游戏
In fact, Fortnite is the biggest free-to-play console game of all time.
它背后的工作室 Epic
The studio behind it, Epic,
还创建了《堡垒之夜》所使用的虚幻游戏引擎
also created the Unreal game engine, which Fortnite uses.
很多其他的游戏也都使用虚幻引擎
Lots of other games use Unreal, tool,
因为 Epic 向世界免费发布了虚幻引擎
because Epic released the Unreal engine to the world for free.
它不是直接开源的 但它的源代码是可访问的
It's not straight-up open source, but it is source-accessible.
这远超了大多数的游戏工作室
And that's well beyond what most studios do.
有了虚幻引擎 任何人都可以获取到源代码
With Unreal engine, anybody can grab the source code.
他们不仅提供了代码
They didn't just make the code available though,
还致力于建立一个答案中心、论坛、开发者支持
they committed to building an answer hub, forums, developer support.
Epic 正在加倍努力建设社区 使其尽可能地广大
Epic is doubling down on building as big and broad a community as possible.
而且他们并不孤单
And they're not alone.
你已经有了像 Godot 和 MonoGame 这样的完整的开源游戏引擎
You've got full-on open source game engines like Godot and MonoGame,
它们正在催生自己的开发社区
which are spawning their own development communities.
红帽公司的软件工程师 Jared Sprague 是新一代的一员
Jared Sprague, a software engineer over at Red Hat,
他们可以使用所有这些工具和引擎来构建令人惊叹的游戏
is part of a new generation that gets to use all these tools and engines to build amazing games
如果没有这些社区 他们是永远不可能创造出这种东西的
they could never have built without those communities.
独立游戏行业最近发展很快
The indie game industry has grown a lot recently.
因此 你应该发现几年前
So you've seen a while ago, like several years ago,
大多数游戏都是由大型工作室制作的
most of the games were made by big studios.
这些都还在市场上 对吧 任天堂之类的
Those are still all out there, right, Nintendo and stuff.
独立游戏产业正在爆炸式增长
The indie industry has exploded.
我认为这很大程度上是因为 Steam
And I think a lot of that is due to Steam, actually.
他说的就是 Steam 平台
That'd be the Steam platform
它让开发者可以将
that lets developers incorporate things like
游戏内聊天功能、社交网络服务等所有好的东西整合在一起
in-game chat functionality, social-networking services, all that good stuff
他们在这方面已经做了 15 年了
They've been at this for about 15 years.
Steam 使任何游戏开发者
Steam made it possible for any game developer
都有可能发布一款游戏给数百万人
to get a game out in front of millions of people.
有很多著名游戏最开始是独立游戏
There've been lots of big games that started as an indie,
也许只有一两个人在做 最后大放异彩
maybe just one or two people working on it that just exploded.
《我的世界》就是一个很好的例子
Minecraft is a perfect example.
刚开始 只有一个人 是独立开发者
Started, just a guy, indie developer.
现在这是有史以来影响力最大的游戏之一
And now it's one of the biggest games ever in history.
但这只是一个例子
But it's just an example of
说明独立游戏是如何真正成为游戏行业的主要力量
how indie has really become a major force in the game industry.
Jared 与他的红帽伙伴 Michael Clayton
Jared's teamed up with his Red Hat pal, Michael Clayton,
合作举办了 gamejams
to produce game jams,
一群独立游戏开发人员聚集在一起
where a bunch of indie game developers get together
在短时间中制作游戏 就像黑客松一样 但用于游戏
and build games in a short amount of time. Like a hackathon, but for games.
GitHub 上有一个叫做 Game Off 的版本
GitHub has one called Game Off.
Jared 的版本叫做 Open Jam
Jared's version is called Open Jam.
他会说这是基于社区的游戏开发未来的一部分
If you ask him, it's part of a community-based game development future
其前景极为广大
that could get much, much bigger.
例如 你可以使用 Linux
You could use, like Linux,
因为它是开源的 所有人都可以为它做贡献
Because it was open source and all these people could contribute to it
添加工具、补丁等等
and add tools and patches and stuff
这就是它如此伟大的原因
is what it made it so great.
比一个人独自完成的要好得多
Way better than just one person could do on their own.
而且我认为开源的游戏 或游戏系统 或者说虚拟世界仍有潜力
And I think there's still potential for a game or some sort of game system or virtual world that was open source,
成千上万的人能在其中贡献 做得比一个人多得多
that thousands of people could contribute to build something bigger than one person could do.
游戏工作室对开源的态度已然开始转变
It's already starting to happen, a shift towards open source attitudes in the gaming studios.
我认为 一旦社区能在游戏的基础上发挥创造力
I think the power of being able to enable your community to create
它的这种力量是毋庸置疑的
is unquestioned.
Jordan Weisman 是 Harebrained Schemes 的联合创始人
Jordan Weisman's the co-founder of Harebrained Schemes.
《血色苍穹》、 《暴战机甲兵》、《机甲战士》这些都是他的作品
Crimson Skies, Battle Tech, Mech Warrior, those are all his.
注：三者皆为上世纪末的游戏 IP，在欧美较为著名。其中，后两者在近年仍有新作。
其中 Crimson Skies 似乎没有官方的中文译名
他长期从事游戏开发
He's been deep in game development a long time.
而他现在看到的是
And what he's seeing now is a shift
随着工作室开始意识到好处 他们对开源的态度也在转变
toward open source attitudes as studios start to realize the benefits.
甚至像《暴战机甲兵》之类的游戏也有很多…
Even games like Battle Tech, which have a fair amount of ...
我们已经尝试向玩家开放尽可能多的游戏数据
We've tried to open up as much of the data of the game as possible to the audience.
而且我们已经看到玩家为游戏提供了惊人的 MOD
And we've seen the audience come up with amazing mods for the game.
我们很高兴能看到
And it's super exciting for us to see
他们如何发挥创造力 又创造出如何的成果
their creativity goes and what they've accomplished.
它们以和游戏本身内容不同的方式吸引着玩家
And it engages players in different ways than our original content has.
这只是关于你能做什么的一个小例子
And that's a small example of what you can do.
随着游戏的发展
And as we go forward with our games,
我们更加知晓了这一点 越来越开放
we're leaning on that even heavier, opening up more and more
让玩家表达他们的创造力
to allow players to express their creativity.
Jordan 认为 制作 MOD 的文化有助于使他的游戏尽善尽美
Jordan figures that a modifying culture helps his games become the best they can be.
但是你知道
But, you know,
就像我们在本期节目的《D＆D》开场白中所暗示的那样
like we hinted at with our D&D opener to this episode,
对社区的推动始终存在
that drive toward community was always there.
TRPG 来自于 GM 与玩家之间
They come from tabletop roots
互相用语言编织一场冒险的 RPG 游戏
where it was a collaborative storytelling experience among the people at the table
人们围坐在一张桌子前合作讲故事并分享经验
between the game master and the players in an RPG.
在某段时间内 当我们开始分享某些电子游戏时
And as we moved into digital forms of those kinds of games, for a period of time,
这两派非常分裂
that was very separated.
我认为 随着 MOD 工具和大家都能接触的引擎的诞生
I think, as modding tools and democratization of the engines and tools
工具变得更易获得 和开发商转向开源
that are accessible and moving to open sourcing,
让我们重新回到了游戏的创建之初
it kind of moves us back closer to that collaborative nature of creating
这种非常社交化的 具有协作性的娱乐方式
this very social form of entertainment.
所以我觉得这很令人兴奋
So I think that's very exciting.
我也这样认为
I think so too.
至于 Jared Sprague
As for Jared Sprague,
他将再次与 Michael Clayton 合作
he's teaming up with Michael Clayton, again,
开发一款全新的社区驱动的开源游戏
to build a brand new, community-driven, open source game.
它被称为…
And it's called...
《代码英雄》
Command Line Heroes.
*庆贺吧！*
是的 我们正式成为一个多平台 IP
Yep, we're officially a multi platform IP.
当然 《代码英雄》游戏将成为一个开源项目
And naturally, the Command Line Heroes game is going to be an open source project.
所以我们邀请社区（也就是你）
So we're inviting the community, that's you, yes you,
与我们一起打造这款游戏
to build this game with us.
我们所要做的就是一个目标
All we're starting with is a single objective.
灵感来自 NASA 这将是一场火星之旅
Inspired by NASA, this is going to be a journey to Mars.
它的细节？
The details?
这将由我们共同决定
That's up to all of us, working together to hammer out.
它会是一款线上游戏
It'll be a Web-based game,
我们将在整整这一季的播客节目里致力于这项工作
and we'll be working on it throughout this season of the podcast.
GitHub 仓库将对任何想要贡献的人开放
The GitHub repos will be available to anybody who wants to contribute.
而且 再说一次 如果你正在收听此内容
And, again, if you're listening to this,
与我们一起开发该游戏
you are invited to get involved to build that game with us.
设计一个角色 提一个拉取请求
Design a character, make a pull request.
或者只是玩测试版 然后将你的反馈发送给我们
Or just play the beta and send us your feedback.
我们将利用我们在本期节目中谈到的所有开源魔法
We're taking all the open source magic we talk about on this show
共同创造一些东西
and using it to build something together.
趣事：
Fun fact:
还记得《巨洞探险》吗？
remember Colossal Cave Adventure?
好吧 虽然这个游戏的代码一直可以访问的
Well, while the code for that game was always accessible,
但《巨洞探险》在 40 年后终于完全开源了
Colossal finally went fully open source after 40 years.
2017 年 官方版本在 BSD 许可证下发布了
In 2017, the official version was released under a BSD Two Clause license.
从最初的互动式文字游戏开始
Gaming communities have come a long way
游戏社区已经走过了很长一段路
since those first interactive words.
*BGM*
你站在一条路的尽头…
You are standing at the end of a road...
问题是 我们不是站在路的尽头
And the thing is, we're not standing at the end of the road.
这条游戏之路绵延不绝
This gaming road goes on and on.
在此过程中 游戏正在帮助我们联合起来 创造出一整个宇宙
And along the way, games are helping us team up and build whole universes.
坦率地说
Frankly,
我们不知道我们的社区将如何安排自己沿着这条路走下去
we don't know how our community will arrange themselves down this road.
但我们知道游戏将会推动这一进程
But we do know games will be driving it.
因为我们从来没有停止过 - 按下启动键
Because we never stop pressing start.
想了解更多关于早期开源社区和开源游戏起源的知识吗？
Want to learn more about early open source community and the origins of open source gaming?
在代码英雄网站上有更多的内容等着你
There's loads more content waiting for you over at the Command Line Heroes website.
你可以通过访问 redhat.com/comandlineheros 更深入地挖掘
You can dig deeper by visiting redhat.com/comandlineheroes.
在我们告别之前 我想让你知道我们在导语中有一项特殊礼物在等着你
Before we say goodbye, I want to let you know about a special treat we've got waiting for you over in the show notes.
这是关于 Warren Robinett 的故事
It's the story of Warren Robinett,
他创造了 Atari 游戏《冒险》
who created the Atari game Adventure,
这款游戏的灵感来自于《巨洞探险》
a game inspired by Colossal Cave Adventure.
他告诉我们 他与老板的争论是
He tells us how a run-in with his bosses
如何导致了电子游戏史上的第一个彩蛋的出现
led to the creation of the very first video game Easter egg.
这是一个很棒的故事
It's a great story.
是软件开发史上很可爱的一部分
A lovely part of our development history,
但我们想给它应有的空间
but we wanted to give it the space it deserves.
所以请到 redhat.com/commandlineheroes 网站上听一听
So take a listen over at redhat.com/commandlineheroes.
代码英雄是 Red Hat 的原创播客
Command Line Heroes is an original podcast from Red Hat.
在 Apple Podcast、Google Podcast 或任何你收听播客的地方免费收听它
Listen for free on Apple Podcasts, Google Podcasts, or wherever you do your thing.
我是 Saron Yitbarek
I'm Saron Yitbarek,
下次见 编程不止
until next time, keep on coding.